电视节目:那好,你说说看,
TV: Alright, come on now, help me out here.
让大家做个见证,
Tell our audience when you first realized you would rather be a woman
你什么时候开始认识到自己更愿像个淑女?上高中的时候?
in high school.
电视节目:当然不是,读高中的时候,我是一名很出色的棒球运动员.
TV 2: By the time I was a senior I was quite a baton twirler.
迈克:嗨!你们俩看见妈妈和爸爸没?
Mike: Eh, have you guys seen Mom and Dad?
电视节目:从那时起,我就觉得自己骨子里更像个男人!
TV 2: From then on, I knew I was a female trapped in a male body.
迈克:嘿,开萝尔,那不跟你一样?
Mike: Hey, Carol, somebody else with your problem.
开萝尔:迈克,你能不能成熟点?
Carol: Mike, when are you gonna grow up?
迈克:现在就告诉你,迈克·西维尔已经长大成人!
Mike: For your information today, Mike Seaver became a man.
本:那今早你是什么?
Ben: Who were you this morning?
迈克:今早还只是个给伯尼洗车的小屁孩,不过,现在已经是个男子汉了!
Mike: Just at boy with a job at Bernie's car wash, but not anymore.
开萝尔和本:伯尼把他给炒了.
Carol/Ben: Bernie fired him.
麦琪:你被解雇了?
Maggie: You were fired?
迈克:不是被解雇,而是我不想干了!
Mike: I wasn't fired!I quit!
杰森:不管怎样,我们讲好了的,你找不到工作,我就不给你买车!!明白吗?
Jason: Either way our deal was no job, no car.
迈克:不管,老爸,
Mike: But Dad, I have a job, it's a great job, an incredible job.
我找到工作了,而且是一份很不错的工作.今天真是太让人高兴了,
Oh god, this is so exciting,
先坐下来,不然你们听了或许会头晕.
you guys might get a little dizzy when I tell you.You better sit.
杰森:说来听听,或许我能撑得住!
Jason: I'll take my chances.
迈克:行!怎么都行!
Mike: Okay, okay, you two are looking at the newest member of the sales
那你们听好了,
force at Stereo Village.
我现在受雇于一家音响设备店,负责营销工作.
That's right, I am one of the lucky,
按最低市场价格出售音响设备和计算机元件,
lucky few who has been given a shot at unlimited earnings selling quality
老板同意按销售利润提成,多劳多得.
audio, video, and computer components at rock bottom prices!
杰森:我看我还是坐下来比较好.
Jason: I better sit down.
迈克:我早说过,你们听了准会头晕.
Mike: I warned you guys.
我很想跟大家好好聊聊我的新工作,
Look, I'd love to chat about this some more but I'm going to be late for
不过我得去上班,不然就迟到了.
the first night of work so.
麦琪:迈克,你该说的还没说完呢?
Maggie: Mike we're not finished talking.
迈克:嗯,行了,妈妈!该说的我都告诉你们了,还想知道点别的?
Mike: Well, gee Mom, I don't know what else I could possibly tell you guys.
杰森:那你说说你是怎么找到这份工作的?为谁工作,
Jason: Well, how about how did you hear about this job?
工作时间?
Who are you working for, what are your hours?
麦琪:工作后你有时间学习吗?
Maggie: How you're going to get your homework done?
杰森:薪水是多少?
Jason: How much does it pay?
麦琪:这份工作合法吗?
Maggie: Is it legal?
迈克:够了,就此打住!
Mike: Hold it.
麦琪:迈克,你看来有点找不着北了.
Maggie: Mike, you look a little dizzy maybe you'd better sit down.
迈克:得了吧!我倒是觉得你们对我一点信心都没有.
Mike: Come on, I get the feeling that you guys have no faith in me at
我以前做过什么才使你们老是这么看我?
all.What have I ever done to make you feel that way?
杰森和麦琪:【无语】
Jason/Maggie: [incoherent]
迈克:行了,我就知道你们会这样.
Mike: Alright, alright.
杰森:那好,迈克,你给我们好好说说你的新工作,但不要胡说八道.
Jason: Ok Mike, tell us about the new job and don't sound like a game show host.
迈克:好,我和波纳每周只需在放学后工作三个下午再加上星期六一整天就可以了!
Mike: Ok, ok.I just work three afternoons after school and on Saturdays, with Boner
麦琪:还有呢?
Maggie: Go on.
迈克:工作地点就在女性内衣专卖店的隔壁.
Mike: And okay, in the stores it's just right at the street in the mall
next to that shop that sells the sexy underwear for women
杰森:这地方我倒也知道,我经常去那边理发.
Jason: I know the place.I get my haircut near there.
麦琪:那薪水怎么算?
Maggie: So how much does this job pay?
迈克:多劳多得,妈妈.
Mike: Well, it's a job in sales, Mom
杰森:到底是多少?
Jason: How much?
迈克:不大好说.
Mike: Well, it's kinda hard to say.
杰森:说来听听!!
Jason: How much?
迈克:事实上,
Mike: Well, see, when you sell things you get a commission,
东西卖掉后就会按价格的百分之十提成,
and I'd be getting ten percent of everything I sell.
这才叫多劳多得.
I mean, this could be worth thousands guys.
杰森:也就是说,没有基本工资?
Jason: So it has no base salary whatsoever?
迈克:爸爸,我知道这可能有点让人难以置信,
Mike: Now Dad, I know this isn't going to be easy but I sure can't spend
可我总不能下半辈子就靠洗车过日子吧?
the rest of my life at that car wash.
麦琪:嗯,杰森,你怎么看?
Maggie: Well Jason, what do you think?
杰森:我看可以,儿子!
Jason: Ok, Mike.
迈克:谢谢爸爸妈妈,
Mike: Alright, thanks guys, thanks, I gotta go change for work.
我得工作去了.老板安德鲁说不准迟到,
Um, I can't be late, Andrew has this policy,
规定不能以任何理由为迟到辩解.
says tardiness is unacceptable for any reason.
麦琪:哪个安德鲁?
Maggie: Who's Andrew?
迈克:他是店经理.再见.
Mike: Oh, he's the manager of the whole store.See you later.
杰森:那他姓什么?
Jason: What's his last name?
迈克:呃【支支吾吾】,这个……
Mike: Uh [Mumbles] take it easy.
杰森:姓什么?
Jason: What?
迈克:戴利斯,再见.
Mike: Delish, see you later.
麦琪:戴利斯?就是那个被学校开除的杰瑞·戴利斯?
Maggie: Delish?He wouldn't be related to Jerry High school drop out Delish, would he
迈克:没错,就是他.
Mike: Well.
杰森:嗯,就是那个和你一起被警察拘过的杰瑞·戴利斯?
Jason: Or Jerry.Hi, we're both in jail Delish?
迈克:嗯,你们刚才说什么来着?
Mike: Uh, actually What was the question again?
麦琪:你所说的安德鲁·戴利斯是不是就是那个经常惹麻烦,
Maggie: Is Andrew Delish related to that jerk that used to get you into
而且总是把你也连累进去的混蛋?
trouble all the time?
迈克:他们很熟.
Mike: Related?Um, they're very close.
杰森:熟到什么程度?
Jason: How close?
迈克:其实就是同一个人.
Mike: Same guy.
麦琪:迈克,我们不是不许你和杰瑞·戴利斯来往了吗?
Maggie: Mike didn't we forbid you to associate with Jerry Delish?
迈克:没错,但你们没禁止我和安德鲁来往啊!!
Mike: Yea, but you didn't say anything about Andrew.
杰森:行了!这跟安德鲁有什么关系?那他为什么要改名?
Jason: C'mon, what's this Andrew business?Why'd he change his name?
迈克:嗯,我想这个不说你们也明白,爸爸!!
Mike: Well, I think it's kind of obvious, Dad.
杰森:当然是为了不被警察逮着.
Jason: Yea, to throw the cops off the trail.
迈克:爸爸,
Mike: No, no, Dad, see,
事情不是你想的那样.
he wanted to change his life around so he started with his name.
他改名是为了重新做人,他现在是批发店的经理.
I mean, Dad, he's the manager of the whole store.
你们不是常说要给人改过自新的机会吗,
And you're the one who's always saying we should believe the best in people,
那为什么不相信杰瑞呢?
so why not give Jerry the benefit of the doubt?
杰森:嗯,就依你!那你怎么想,麦琪?
Jason: Well, um, ok what do you think Maggie?
麦琪:我没意见.
Maggie: I'll agree with your decision.
杰森:那好,迈克,那你就闯闯吧.
Jason: Alright, Mike, give it a shot.
迈克:谢谢你,爸爸!
Mike: Hey, thanks a lot, Dad.
麦琪:其实,我心里却不这样看.
Maggie: That wasn't the decision I was going to agree with.
杰森:迈克,如果你去工作,
Jason: You know, if you're going to deal with the public,
那我建议你穿着正式一点.
you'll need a nice conservative suit.
迈克:得了吧,爸爸,我只是去卖音响设备,又不是去干别的.
Mike: Come on, Dad.I'm just selling stereos.
杰森:穿着正式一点有什么不对?
Jason: Well, yea, but it never hurts to look sharp.
迈克:嗯说得没错,那这套衣服怎么样?
Mike: Uh huh.Tell me about it.
本:妈妈,你是不是生来就是女人?
Ben: Mom, were you always a woman?
麦琪:当然不是,我以前可是个小女孩.
Maggie: No.I used to be a little girl.
本:噢,我说得没错吧,开萝尔.
Ben.Oh.I told you Carol!
麦琪:杰森,你怎么就准许迈克去为杰瑞·戴利斯工作?
Maggie: Jason, why did you tell Mike he could work for Jerry Delish?
杰森:亲爱的,那天你走了以后,
Jason: Well, honey after you left, I got to hear Jerry's philosophy,
我跟杰瑞聊了一会,对杰瑞的一些想法多少有点了解,
the road to success is hard work.
他认为成功是要努力的.
And don't expect others to make it easy for you.
不能老是期待他人为你做这做那.人人都得对自己负责.
Each of us is responsible for himself.
麦琪:果真如此?
Maggie: Really?
杰森:当然.他让迈克生活有了目标,
Jason: Really.He's got Mike wanting to be prompt and dependable.
这可是我多年来都没做到的事情.
Things I've been trying to make him think about for years.
麦琪:好吧,听你的.
Maggie: Gee.
杰森:其实要不是我对自己这么有信心,
Jason: If I wasn't so darn confident of myself,
或许多少会对杰瑞有点羡慕.
I might even be a little jealous.
开萝尔:我宣布自己从没说过你能成为真正的男人.
Carol: I would just like to state for the record that I never once suggested
that you might have been a man.
麦琪:他们两个又在吵什么?
Maggie: What the heck are they watching in there, anyway?
迈克:别忘了带着你的亲朋好友一起光临本店.
Mike: And don't forget to send your friends in.
购物者甲:要是产品有问题怎么办?
Customer: Uh, if I have a problem with my unit.
迈克:尽管来找我好啦.
Mike: Call me.
购物者甲:那就好.
Customer: I will.
波纳:你看怎么样?
Boner: So, what do you think?
购物者乙:感觉你有点靠不住!!
Customer2: I think you're dangerous!
迈克:波纳,你干什么呢?
Mike: Boner, what are you doing?
波纳:刚才那人是想来换点零钱,不过我却一个劲的劝他买音响,
Boner: All's I know is I got a guy looking at a couple of speakers who
结果你也看见了.
only wanted change for the parking meter, I say I did a lot.
迈克:要记住安德鲁说过的话,
Mike: Look, remember what Andy says,
好的推销员能把冰箱卖给爱斯基摩人.
a good salesman could sell a refrigerator to an Eskimo.
波纳:不过,爱斯基摩人好像用不着……噢,噢,噢……
Boner: Well, an Eskimo wouldn't need a Ohhh.
迈克:明白就好.
Mike: Yea.
波纳:那我再去试试.
Boner: Ok, I'll give it another shot.
迈克:正该如此.
Mike: That's right.
波纳:嘿,各位走过路过,千万不要错过,本电产品物美价廉.西维尔大夫,怎么你也想买……
Boner: Hello and welcome to Stereo Village, where quality and value Dr.Seaver!
杰森:你好啊,波纳!
Jason: Hi, Boner!
波纳:叫我理查德!
Boner: It's Richard here.
杰森:怎么?你也改名了?!
Jason: You changed your name, too?
波纳:没有啊,我一直都叫理查德,
Boner: No, it's always been Richard.
不过那个名字不大好听,所以就不怎么用.
I just don't use it 'cause it's a dumb sounding name.
杰森:想得不错啊,波纳!
Jason: Good thinking, Boner.
波纳:迈克,快过来,看看是谁来了.
Boner: Hey, Mikey, look who's here.
迈克:请您稍等.
Mike: Ah, excuse me a second.
杰森:嗨,迈克.
Jason: Hi Mike.
迈克:嘿,波纳你先去招呼我的顾客,我来招呼我爸!
Mike: Ah, Boner, can you take care of my customer while I take care of my dad?
波纳:行,我倒宁愿卖东西给你老爸,不过那个人也行.
Boner: Well, I'd rather sell to your dad Oh, ok.
迈克:爸爸,你来这里做什么?
Mike: So, Dad, uh, what are you doing here?
杰森:我想有没有什么便宜货可以买.
Jason: I'm just taking advantage of Stereo Village's grand opening sale.
迈克:是来跟踪我的吧!
Mike: Checkin' up on me.
杰森:开玩笑,迈克,我跟踪你干嘛.
Jason: Oh, come on, Mike.I'm not checking up on you.
好啦,我承认,我是想过来看看.
Ok, I'm checking up on you.So, sue me.
迈克:爸爸,你怎么……
Mike: Dad, uh...
杰森:我说得没错吧,穿着正式一点,感觉还好吧?!
Jason: I see you took my advice about the suit.
迈克:我同意,就像安德鲁所说人靠衣装.
Mike: Well, yea, yea, like Andrew says, dress for success.
安德鲁:嘿,迈克,有空了干点别的,别老是东拉西扯.噢,西维尔大夫.
Andrew: Hey, Michael, when you get the chance Dr.Seaver.
杰森:杰瑞,哦,对不起,安德鲁.
Jason: Jerry.Uh, Andrew.
安德鲁:自从你把我和迈克从警局保释出来后,我们再也没碰过面.
Andrew: I haven't seen you since you bailed Michael and me out of jail.
杰森:是啊!
Jason: Yea.
迈克:爸爸,已经时过境迁了!
Mike: And that was a very long time ago, Dad.
杰森:嗯,没错.
Jason: That's right.
安德鲁:吃一堑,长一智!
Andrew: Well, I think Michael and I have done quite a bit of growing up
从那以后,我和迈克都成熟稳重多了.
since then.
波纳:迈克,你看看又是谁来了!!
Boner: Mikey, look who else is here!
麦琪:杰森,你来这干什么?
Maggie: Jason, what are you doing here?
迈克:跟你一样,跟踪我来着.
Mike: He's checking up on me, same as you.
麦琪:不是你想得那样,孩子.
Maggie: Oh.Oh, no, no, no honey.
我只是想在隔壁的女性内衣专卖店买点东西而已.
I just happened to be shopping in the lingerie store next door.
杰森:真的吗?
Jason: Really?
迈克:呃,妈妈,你还记得杰瑞·戴利斯吗?
Mike: Uh, Mom, you remember Jerry Delish, don't you?
麦琪:那个混蛋,他在哪?
Maggie: That dirt bag, where is he?
安德鲁:现在人称安德鲁的就是在下.
Andrew: It's Andrew now.
麦琪:噢,天哪,令人刮目相看!!
Maggie: Oh my goodness, you've changed.
安德鲁:您还好吧,西维尔夫人?
Andrew: How are you doing, Mrs.Seaver?
你们夫妇俩一定和我一样为迈克而自豪吧!
You two must be just as proud of Michael as I am.
杰森:未请教?
Jason: Why?
安德鲁:你们不知道?迈克不过来了四天,
Andrew: Why?You don't know?Michael here has outsold everybody.
却比谁都强.
It's his first four days.
麦琪:真是了不起,迈克,那你为什么不告诉我们?
Maggie: That's wonderful, Michael, why didn't you tell us?
迈克:我只是想给你们一个惊喜.
Mike: Well, I just thought I'd surprise you.
安德鲁:没错,他的确让我大吃一惊.没有比他工作更卖力的了.
Andrew: Well, he sure did surprise me.I've never seen a harder worker.
迈克:我很想跟你们多聊会,不过那边有顾客等着我,
Mike: Well, look, I'd love to talk to you guys,
所以……
but I have a customer over here who needs some help.
迈克:没问题,瞧我的!
Mike: Ok.
安德鲁:西维尔大夫,
Andrew: Dr.Seaver, Mrs.
西维尔夫人,
Seaver, I just wanted to tell you,
说句心里话,谢谢你们不计较我曾给迈克招来那么多麻烦,
I'm deeply touched that you overlooked all that stupid trouble I used
还同意迈克来这工作,
to get Mikey into and took a chance and let Michael work here.
如此心胸宽广的父母已经不多见了.
Not many parents would do that.
安德鲁:搞定他,迈克.
Andrew: Go get him, Mike.
麦琪:没事,浪子回头金不换!!
Maggie: Heck, anybody could end up in jail.
安德鲁:总之,你遇到二位深感荣幸.
Andrew: Well, it was a pleasure to see you both.
杰森:没事,谢谢你,杰瑞.
Jason: Alright.Thank you, Jerry.
麦琪:谢谢你,杰瑞,噢,应该称呼安德鲁才对.
Maggie: Thank you, Jerry.Andrew.
杰森:对对,是安德鲁没错.
Jason: It's Andrew.
麦琪:谢谢.
Maggie: Thanks.
购物者丙:这些东西真有你们宣传的那么好吗?
Customer: Is this radio cassette/TV thing any good?
迈克:说实话,这东西并非物有所值.
Mike: Oh, yes, yes.I can't lie to you, Ed.It's really not worth the price.
埃德:真的?
Ed: Yea?
迈克:真的!!
Mike: Yea.
杰森:这小子干得不错嘛!!
Jason: That's my boy!
麦琪:我不是说过了吗,迈克干这工作肯定行.
Maggie: I told you Mike taking this job was a good idea.
杰森:嘿,话怎么都让你给说了?!
Jason: Oh, come on, you were so unsure.
本:这不公平!不公平!不公平!!
Ben: It's not fair!It's not fair!It's not fair.
开萝尔:盘子还没洗干净!!
Carol: It's not clean!
迈克:你们俩看见爸爸妈妈没?
Mike: Have you guys seen Mom and Dad?
本:迈克,该你洗盘子了.
Ben: Mike, it's your turn to do the dishes.
迈克:今晚不行,班尼!妈妈?爸爸?
Mike: Not tonight, Benny.Mom?Dad?
开萝尔:你以为没在家里吃饭,
Carol: You think just because you didn't dirty any of these dishes you
就不用洗盘子!?
can get out of washing them.
迈克:开萝尔,今晚你看起来真漂亮.
Mike: You're looking good tonight, Carol.
杰森:嘿,迈克,我们以为你还在工作呢!
Jason: Hey, Mike!We thought you'd be at work!
本和开萝尔:又被炒了!!
Ben and Carol: Fired again.
迈克:当然不是,说来肯定会让你们大吃一惊,
Mike: No, see, this is the big surprise that I was telling you about.
老板第一次给我发工钱,而且还不少.
I just got my first commission check and it was major!
大家或许不信,不过现在就让我们全家来分享我的劳动成果,
You guys aren't going to believe this.
妈妈,爸爸,
But, um, I thought I'd share some of the wealth with my family.
本,开萝尔都快过来啊!!
Mom, Dad, and Ben, and Carol.
本:什么事这么着急?
Ben: What the heck's going on here?
迈克:快点打开来看看!
Mike: Just go ahead and open it.
本:哇塞!超级电子游戏机.我现在就想玩了!!
Ben: Wow!Super Veto Brothers in Wyoming.I'm gonna go play this!
开萝尔:迈克,今天太阳从西边出来了?!
Carol: Mike!This is so unlike you.
迈克:随你怎么说,不过你现在你就可以边做减肥操边欣赏了.
Mike: Yea, well, I figured you could use it while you do your aerobics.
开萝尔:我从来就不做什么减肥操!
Carol: Well, I don't do aerobics.
迈克:呃,这个!
Mike: Uh huh.
麦琪:这是电子词典?
Maggie: It's a thesaurus program?
迈克:没错,妈妈,
Mike: Yea, see I figured that, um,
是专门为你准备的.你写稿子的时候,
you know when you're writing your stories and you need a word that means
如若需要查询一个词的近义词,
the same as the one you've already used you just press a button and this
只需简单操作几下,这个电子词典就能让你如愿.
gives you a whole bunch of other words.
麦琪:噢,迈克,亏你这么孝顺,知道体贴周到地关心妈妈.
Maggie: Oh, Michael, this is so sweet, thoughtful, considerate, caring.
杰森:好像词典也在其次了!
Jason: Sounds like she doesn't need a thesaurus.
麦琪:儿子,你能这样,妈妈真的很高兴,谢谢!!
Maggie: I'm gonna cry, thank you.
迈克:妈妈,这是儿子应当做的.
Mike: You're welcome.
杰森:迈克,你真行!
Jason: Mike, you amaze me.
迈克:嗯,谢谢你能相信我,爸爸!这是给你的爸爸,打开看看!!
Mike: Well, thanks for believing in me, Dad.Hey, go on, go ahead, open it up.
杰森:噢,太好了,哇噢!迈克,好儿子!
Jason: Oh, ok.Oh, hey Mike this is terrific.
迈克:嗯哼,
Mike: Yea, yea, I figured that, uh,
你把这台袖珍电视放在办公室里,这样就能在病人说话的时候,
you know you could put it in your office so that when your patients are
观看电视节目了.
talking you could watch some TV.
杰森:我不是有意扫你的兴,
Jason: I don't mean to sound ungrateful,
你不是跟客人说过,
but isn't this the model that you told that guy in the store that would
买这玩艺儿根本就是在浪费钱吗?.
be a waste of his money?
迈克:我是这么说过,不过那只是推销而已,爸爸.
Mike: Oh, yea, that was just salesmanship, Dad.
杰森:不太了解.
Jason: I don't understand.
迈克:这些小玩意只是用来吸引顾客而已,
Mike: Oh, well, see, see that's the model we use to lure them into the store.
他们一旦踏进店门,
It's my job to hook em, reel em in,
我们就会有办法让他花大钱买其他东西.
and get them to spend a lot more money.
麦琪:杰森,你能冷静下来,告诉我迈克都干了些什么吗?
Maggie: Jason, would you just calm down and tell me what Mike did?
杰森:他做了什么?这么跟你说吧,
Jason: What did he do?
这小子在做违法的勾当,离近监狱已经不远了.
Well, he's just taken the first step on the road to Sing Sing.
麦琪:进监狱??
Maggie: Sing Sing?
杰森:没错,那你知道是谁唆使迈克这么做的吗?
Jason: Yea, and you know who's going to be holding the cell door open for him.
麦琪:本?
Maggie: Ben?
杰森:我说的是杰瑞·戴利斯.
Jason: I'm talking about Jerry Delish.
我们俩竟然傻到相信那小子想重新做人,
And you and I were fooled to think that Jerry wasn't Jerry anymore just
仅仅是因为他换了个名字.
because he's Andrew.
麦琪:杰森,你说什么我一点也没听明白,你能别大声吵吵慢慢说吗?
Maggie: Jason I can't follow you when you're ranting.
杰森:我哪里在吵……
Jason: I do not rant.
麦琪:算我说错了,行吗?
Maggie: Oh, no, no, no.Of course you don't.
杰森:别老是顺着我的意思来说.
Jason: And don't just say what I want to hear.
麦琪:好吧,我觉得你太激动了,你到现在还没给我讲清楚,这是为什么.
Maggie: Ok, then, you are getting incredibly carried away and so far you haven't told me what has gotten you so upset.
杰森:那好,你听我说.
Jason: Alright, here it is.It's the Delish philosophy.
戴利斯认为,懒散不是辩解推托的理由,
Tardiness is unacceptable for any reason.The road to success is hard work.
要想成功就得努力,
And get this one, each of us is responsible for himself.
个人要对自己的所作所为负责.他这一套完全被迈克所接受认同.
Mike's buying that a hundred percent.
麦琪:杰森,
Maggie: Jason do you think perhaps you were on to something last week
上周你不也说过安德鲁的成功也让你觉得有点羡慕吗?
when you might be a little jealous of Andrew's influence
杰森:没错,我是说过这话,但你能不能听我把话说完?
Jason: Oh, I was completely off base and frankly, I don't even know why you would listen to me.
麦琪:好吧!你先说.
Maggie: Ok.
杰森:麦琪,你口中说同意,但眼角分明不以为然.
Jason: Maggie, you're saying ok, but your eyes are saying jealous.
麦琪:我的眼睛又不能开口说话,好吧,
Maggie: My eyes didn't open their mouth.
那你说说你不是羡慕是什么?
Now, if it isn't jealousy, what is it, then?
杰森:那你可曾听过放长线钓大鱼?
Jason: Alright, have you ever heard of something called bait and switch?
麦琪:安德鲁就在做这个?
Maggie: Andrew does that?
杰森:我们的好儿子迈克也在做这个!!
Jason: Mike, too!
麦琪:不会吧?!
Maggie: Oh, no!
杰森:没错,事实如此!
Jason: Yes!
麦琪:我要找安德鲁,应该是杰瑞和迈克好好谈谈!
Maggie: Well, I'd like a word with that Andrew, uh, Jerry!And Mike!
杰森:跟他们三个都得谈谈.迈克,在你出去之前,
Jason: Well, I'd like a word with all three of them.
我想跟你说两句话.哇塞,这屋子……
Mike I'd like to talk to you before you whoa.Look at this room!
迈克:有什么不对的地方吗?
Mike: What's wrong with it?
杰森:这么干净.
Jason: It's clean.
迈克:那又怎样!
Mike: Yea.
杰森:这也是安德鲁的好主意?
Jason: This another one of Andrew's suggestions?
迈克:嗯,他说过越是井井有条越对自己有利.
Mike: He says the more organized you are, the better.
杰森:说的没错.
Jason: Oh, I'll bet.
迈克:难道你不想我把房间打扫的干干净净?
Mike: What, you don't want me to clean my room?
杰森:当然想,那要看是为什么!!
Jason: Well, yea, but for the right reasons!
迈克:嗯,爸爸,我得赶回店里工作.安德鲁说了我不能……
Mike: Yea, uh, Dad, listen I got to get back to the store.Andrew says I can't.
杰森:你能不能先坐下来?
Jason: Will you just sit down please?
迈克:当然不行,我回来就是为了清除衣服上的这块污点,
Mike: No, see, the only reason I came home was because I got a stain on
其他的……
my suit.And I ...
杰森:先坐下来,行吗?你自个知不知道你在那店里都干了些什么吗?
Jason: Will you sit?You know what you're doing down there?
迈克:嗯,开始还不太明白,现在已经八九不离十了.这份工作挺有意思的.
Mike: Well, not at first, but now it's kind of fun, I like it.I mean.
杰森:不是这个意思,我是说你诱使顾客花大钱买一些以次充好的商品,
Jason: No, no, I'm talking about when you tell a customer that something
来骗钱,这叫欺诈,
he wants to buy is junk to get him to spend more?
是在犯罪,你懂吗?
It's called bait and switch.It's a con.It's a crime.
迈克:好了,好了!爸爸,进店顾客可自由选择要买还是不买,他们不一定非得按我说的做.
Mike: Now hold on, wait a minute.Dad, now that guy was free to buy anything in the store, he didn't have to listen to me.
杰森:但是,迈克,你在向人家撒谎!
Jason: But, Mike, you lied to him.
迈克:爸爸,我只不过引导顾客去那些我们打算出售的货物.
Mike: Dad, I just nudged him towards some merchandise that we needed to move.
杰森:迈克,你向民众撒谎,
Jason: Mike, you're lying to people.
民众总比你的销售定额重要吧!
People are more important than your sales quotas.
迈克:好了,好了!那你呢?出售旧车的时候,你不也是想尽可能卖个好价钱吗?
Mike: Alright, alright, hold on.Ok, how about you, Dad.Now, when you wanted to get rid of the old car, you wanted to get as much as you could for it, right?
杰森:那又怎样?
Jason: So?
迈克:那又怎样?!!你有没有把汽车的毛病如实告诉给人家啊!?
Mike: So, did you tell the salesperson that the transmission was shot?
杰森:没错,我告诉他了.
Jason: Yes, I did.
迈克:你真的这么做了?
Mike: You did?
杰森:嗯!
Jason: Yea!
迈克:那好,那你交税了没?现在大家都想能少交点税就少交点,对不对?
Mike: Ok, alright, how about the taxes?Alright, now everybody fudges a little bit on their taxes, right?
杰森:可我没这么做.
Jason: Not me.
迈克:嗨,爸爸.
Mike: Oh, Dad, Dad.
这些事全世界的人都知道,怎么唯独就你一无所知呢?!
There's a whole world going on out there that you don't know anything about.
杰森:不要因为这个就觉得你老爸可怜,行吗?
Jason: Don't pity your father, ok?
迈克:当然不会!我想说,你每天早晨起床,穿过起居室到你的办公室,然后整天连门都不出.
Mike: I'm not.I'm not.I'm just saying that, you get up in the morning; you walk across the living room and into your office.I men, you never even go outside.
杰森:真的像你说的那样?那你以为每天的报纸是谁拿回来的?
Jason: Oh, really?Well, who do you think brings in the morning paper?
难道你真以为它们自个就跑进屋子里来?我每天都会出去溜达溜达!
You think it just walks in here by itself?I'm outside every day!
迈克:那你到底要我怎样才行?让我放弃这份工作?
Mike: So what's your point?You gonna make me quit, right?
杰森:我是要你辞职.不是,
Jason: Oh, you bet I'm...
我是想让你辞职,但是……
No, I'd like to, as much as I'd like to, I'm not.
迈克:你不想让我放弃这份工作?
Mike: You're not?
杰森:不想.
Jason: No.
迈克:为什么?
Mike: Why not?
杰森:因为以你的年龄,现在可以自己拿主意了.
Jason: Because you're too old for me to make you do anything.
迈克:真的?
Mike: I am?
杰森:迈克,我总不能管你一辈子!!
Jason: I can't be looking over your should all your life, Mike.
迈克:明白!
Mike: Uh-huh.
杰森:但你始终都得记着,要对自己的所作所为负责.
Jason: You got to learn that the only one responsible for you is you.
迈克:嗯,安德鲁也这么说!!
Mike: Yea, that's exactly what Andrew says!
杰森:这样最好.
Jason: Better.
波纳:迈克,主街道离这是三条街还是四条街?
Boner: Mikey, is Main St.up three blocks or four?
迈克:四条!
Mike: Four.
波纳:嘿,是四条街,
Boner: Hey, great.Four blocks, it's on the corner, Senor Stereo,
叫Senor音响设备商店,很容易找到.
you can't miss it.
购物者(丈夫):嗯,非常感谢!
Customer (Husband): Oh, great.Thanks a lot.
波纳:没什么,甭客气!
Boner: Hey, my pleasure.
购物者(妻子):要不你这么说,
Customer (Wife): If you hadn't of told us,
那我们就会把钱全部浪费在这.
we would have wasted all that money here.
迈克:波纳,你在做什么?
Mike: Boner, what are you doing?
波纳:没什么,他们需要购买一整套音响系统.
Boner: Oh, they needed a whole new stereo system.
迈克:波纳,我们也是做这个的.
Mike: Boner, that's what we sell here.
波纳:我知道,但是Senor商店比我们这儿卖得便宜.他们刚结婚不久,钱又不多.
Boner: I know that, but Senor Stereo's having this Call me Loco sale.Listen, they just got married, so they're kind of broke.
迈克:波纳,那跟你没关系.
Mike: Bone, that's not your problem.
波纳:迈克,如果他们按照店里的价格买一套音响,我就会觉得自己像个小偷.
Boner: Mikey, if I would have stuck them with our prices, I would have felt like a thief.
迈克:谁会叫你小偷啊?
Mike: Who you calling a thief?
波纳:没人会这么叫我,不过我不能引他们上当,
Boner: Nobody.I can't hook em, I can't reel em in.
我的原则是愿者上钩,就像钓鱼一样.
You know how much I like fish.
迈克:波纳,你看你穿的像什么,瞧瞧,这又是什么?
Mike: Boner, you got to straighten up your act, man.Look at you here.What is this?
波纳:我的衬裤,手绢哪都找不到,所以……
Boner: My shorts.I couldn't find a handkerchief.
安德鲁:迈克,有空过来一下,我想跟你说几句话.
Andrew: Michael, when you get a chance, I need to talk to you.
迈克:嗯,好的,安德鲁.有什么你就说吧!
Mike: Yea, sure, Andrew.So, what can I do for you?
安德鲁:我只是想告诉你,迈克,
Andrew: I just want to let you know, Michael,
你是店里最出色的员工.
I think you're doing a one heck of a job.
迈克:是吗?那可多谢了.
Mike: Hey, thanks.
安德鲁:我真的很为你骄傲.
Andrew: You know, I'm really proud of you.
安德鲁:得了,我都从你那学来的!
Mike: Well, I learned from you.
安德鲁:那这周你的提成是多少?
Andrew: What did you do this week in commissions?
迈克:呃,350美元.
Mike: Ah, $350.
安德鲁:那波纳该拿多少?
Andrew: What did Boner do?
迈克:这个……你也瞧见了,波纳他工作很卖力.
Mike: Ah, well, you know he's working real hard out there.
安德鲁:迈克,你也知道,
Andrew: Mike, you know, I've known Boner a long time,
我认识波纳很久了,认识你的时候我就认识他了.
almost as long as I've known you.
据我所知,波纳的提成几乎为零.
As well as I know Boner, I also know he doesn't have it.
迈克:或许他还不怎么熟悉业务,或许见到客人觉得紧张什么的,所以有点手忙脚乱,所以才这样.
Mike: Well, maybe he's just nervous, I mean maybe he just got so much of it, he doesn't know what to do with it.
安德鲁:迈克,你已经赚了350美元,而波纳的业绩才是3.62美元.
Andrew: Michael, you've made $350.Boner has made $3.62.
迈克:是提成还是销售额?
Mike: Is that net or gross?
安德鲁:他总共就这么点销售额.
Andrew: His net is gross.
迈克:得了吧!杰瑞,再给他一次机会,波纳值得我们信赖,他人心地也不错,所以他宁愿不赚钱,也不肯骗顾客.
Mike: C'mon, c'mon, Jer.Just give the guy a break.I mean, he's trustworthy and good hearted, but that guy couldn't tell a lie if his life depended on it.
安德鲁:迈克,你说像他这样能做生意吗?
Andrew: Mike, you know what it takes to sell.
老实讲,
But can you honestly tell me that Boner's gonna have that killer instinct?
波纳能胜任这工作吗?
Now, I know you're a little closer to him than I am so I thought I'd
我知道他跟你比我熟,所以就请你去跟他说说这件事.
ask you if you wanted to tell him.
迈克:跟他说什么?
Mike: Tell him what?
安德鲁:就说他被辞退了.
Andrew: Well, he's gone.
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
安德鲁:这是在做生意,明白吗?这件事就交给你了.
Andrew: Hey, this is business.You want to tell him?
迈克:要我去说?
Mike: Me?
安德鲁:马上就要下班了,这是总得有人去说,
Andrew: It's closing time, somebody's got to.
而我认为由你去说比较好.
I just thought he'd take it better from you.
购物者:那这个元件的功率有多大?
Customer: So, uh, how many watts per channel is this?
迈克:40瓦.
Mike: Huh?Oh, um, 40 watts.
我们一会就要下班了,您先好好考虑考虑,
Listen we've got a few minutes before closing and why don't you think
我去去就来.
it over and I'll be right back.
波纳:这是你要的二极管,里面有张一块两毛的发票.
Boner: Here is your diode.And your recent for a buck twenty's in the bag.
谢谢.这下我又赚了一毛二!
Enjoy!That's twelve more cents right in my pocket.
购物者:请问一下,你们店里有没有霹雳二号音响系统?
Customer: Excuse me, do you carry the Thunderclap Two System?
迈克:嗯,那当然,请进!
Mike: Uh, yea, yea.We got it.
购物者:东西在哪?
Customer: And?
迈克:实在对不起,先生!今天我工作了一整天,感觉有点累.我们店里有霹雳二号音响系统,就让理查德给您介绍一下.你给这位先生介绍一下霹雳二号音响系统.
Mike: I'm sorry sir, I'm sorry.It's been a long day.Yes, we do carry
the Thunderclap Two System and I'd be happy to, uh,
to have Richard here demonstrate
it for you.Could you, uh, please show this gentleman the Thunderclap Two System
波纳:这东西很贵!!
Boner: Oh, that's expensive.
迈克:这边请,先生.
Mike: Right this way sir.
安德鲁:迈克,要关门了,你赶紧着!
Andrew: Michael, it's almost closing time.
迈克:知道啦,杰瑞!再给波纳一点时间,他正向顾客推销我们店里最贵的音响系统.
Mike: Yea, I know, I know, Jer.Just give him a minute, he's about to move the highest priced system in the store.
波纳:这边请!!
Boner: You're right, it is this way.
迈克:好了,咱哥们谁跟谁,你说是不?他也是你哥们.生意得做,但也得顾着哥们啊.
Mike: Oh, come on, just for old time's sake, alright?I mean, I mean, he's
your buddy, too.Andrew:
There's a time for buddies and there's a time for business
购物者:真是不知道怎么感谢你才好.
Customer: I can't thank you enough.
波纳:嘿,客气什么,做朋友是干什么的.
Boner: Hey, tell a friend.
迈克:看见了吧,
Mike: Boy, that was quick.
出手不凡!我们帮你把这套音响搬上车,
Well, uh, we'd be happy to help you load your components into your car
先生.
for you, sir.
购物者:谢谢,我再等等.
Customer: No, I can wait.
波纳跟我说,
The Bone here tipped me to the Thunderclap Two's gonna be on sale next week.
下周霹雳二号音响系统就会降价,所以我再等等看.
I'll wait until then.
波纳:嘿,到时见,马瑞斯.
Boner: Hey, see you then, Maurice.
购物者:嘿,回见!
Customer: Hey!
波纳:到时候大家一起去钓鱼,成不成?
Boner: So, who else is up for fish and chips, huh?
安德鲁:波纳,你过来一下!
Andrew: Mr.Bone.
迈克:等会,我想跟安德鲁谈谈!!
Mike: Uh, no, wait.Um, I need a moment with Andrew, please.
波纳:那你先来.
Boner: Sure thing.
迈克:杰瑞,你就再给波纳一次机会,行不行?
Mike: Come on, Jer.Just give him one more chance.
安德鲁:他已经错失了好多机会,
Andrew: He's had as many chances as he's gonna get.
我们的销售额总得按时完成吧!!
Now, I've got a sales quota to meet here.
迈克:那我们就得开除波纳吗?他是我们的哥们,他是波纳你明白吗?
Mike: So, what do we do, we just dust Bone?Because he's cause he's Boner?
安德鲁:那又怎样,他什么都卖不动.他跟我们不一样,他总是为客人打算,
Andrew: No, because he can't sell.He's not like us, Mike.
甚至不为自己着想.所以没办法,只能辞掉他.
He's too concerned with the customer and whether they can afford the stuff.
迈克:他这么做有什么错?
Mike: So, what's wrong with that?
安德鲁:迈克,如果你连这点小事情都办不了的话,那我就把你也给辞掉.
Andrew: Mike if you couldn't get rid of this stuff, I'd get rid of you.
迈克:但我们是哥们!
Mike: But we're buddies.
安德鲁:我是在做生意.
Andrew: This is a business.
迈克:这么做生意是不对的.
Mike: But that's... That's wrong.
安德鲁:你到底想说什么?
Andrew: What are you talking about?
迈克:我认为民众什么时候都比销售额要重要的多.
Mike: I'm just saying that people are more important than your sales quotas.
安德鲁:这种破玩意是谁教你的?
Andrew: Who's been handing you that garbage?
迈克:谁?
Mike: Who?I'll tell you who.
告诉你,
Somebody who knows a heck of a lot about the real world out there.
这个人晓畅世事,言必有中,
You know, somebody who always seems to be right and it's really beginning
对他我佩服的五体投地.
to get me tense.
不用你炒我,
You know, I think I might as well just quit this job right now because
哥们现在就不干了!因为他认为我应该辞掉这份烂工作,
that's what he thinks I should do.
所以我就不浪费你的时间了.
And it's probably what I'm gonna end up doing,
再见!
so I'll just save you the time, huh?
安德鲁:嘿,迈克!迈克!迈克!!
Andrew: Hey, Mike.Mike!Mikey!
Mike: Hey, folks!Senor Stereo's got this exact same stuff for half the price
不用我多说了吧!杰瑞,你不是想跟我们去钓鱼吗?
And they care about their customers.Adios, Jer.I thought you wanted some fish.
波纳:哦!明天见,杰瑞.
Boner: Oooo!See you tomorrow, Jer.
迈克:行了,行了,他到底在哪?
Mike: Alright, alright, where is he?
麦琪:你说是谁?
Maggie: Where's who?
迈克:爸爸啊!
Mike: Dad.
麦琪:嗯,他出去散步去了,你的所作所为让他很生气,迈克!
Maggie: Oh, he went for a long walk, he was pretty upset with you, Mike.
迈克:爸爸生我的气?我还生自己的气呢,当然还生他的气!!
Mike: He's upset with me?Well, I'm upset with me.And him, both of us!
麦琪:怎么了?
Maggie: Why?
迈克:怎么了?
Mike: Why?Do you have any idea of what a rotten thing he did to me
或许你还不知道他今天晚上给我给我出的馊主意!!
earlier tonight?
麦琪:不知道,到底是什么?
Maggie: No, what?
迈克:没什么,他眼睁睁地看着我犯错,却不提醒我一下,由着我去犯错.
Mike: Nothing.Yea, nothing.He knew what a major mistake I was going to make and he left it up to me to figure out.
麦琪:你愿意让他看着你的一举一动.
迈克:那当然.不是这样,我是说,在我稀里糊涂地要犯大错的时候,你们伸手拉我一下总可以吧?也许我不该说这些,但这是你们的责任,对不对?嘿,爸爸,你要是老对我这么信任,不知道会什么大乱子.
00:23:00,000
Maggie: Would you prefer that we monitor your every move? Mike: Yes.No, I mean, I just wish that you guys would come down on me when you know I'm going to mess up majorly, alright?I mean, excuse me for saying it, but isn't that your job?Hey, Dad, if you're gonna start treating me with trust and respect, I don't know what's going to happen.